bachtrack.com 2019-03-31

# Privacy notice | by Bachtrack for classical music, opera, ballet and dance event reviews

**Introduction**

Thank you for reading our privacy notice. We respect your privacy and are committed to protecting your personal data. This privacy notice will inform you as to how we look after your personal data and tell you about your privacy rights and how the law protects you.

This privacy notice is provided in a layered format so you ccan click through to the specific areas set out below. Please also use the Glossary to understand the meaning of some of the terms used in this privacy notice.

1\. Important information and who we are

2\. The data we collect about you

3\. How your personal data is collected

4\. How we use your personal data

5\. Disclosures of your personal data

6\. International transfers

7\. Data security

8\. Data retention

9\. Your legal rights

10\. Glossary

**1\. Important information and who we are**

_**Purpose of this privacy notice**_

This privacy notice aims to give you information on how we collect and process your personal data, including any data you may provide to us directly via our website or otherwise.

It is important that you read this privacy notice together with any other privacy notice, fair processing notice or privacy policy we may provide on specific occasions when we are collecting or processing personal data about you so that you are fully aware of how and why we are using your data.

_**Controller**_

Bachtrack Ltd is the controller and responsible for your personal data (referred to as "we", "us" or "our" in this privacy notice).

We have appointed a data privacy manager who is responsible for overseeing questions in relation to this privacy notice. If you have any questions about this privacy notice, including any requests to exercise your legal rights, please contact the data privacy manager using the details set out below.

_**Contact details**_

Our full details are:

Full name of legal entity: Bachtrack Ltd.

Name or title of data privacy manager: David Karlin.

Email address: webmaster@bachtrack.com.

Postal address: Unit 5, The Courtyard, 50 Lynton Road, London, N8 8SL, United Kingdom.

Telephone number: +44(0)20 8004 1072.

You have the right to make a complaint at any time to the Information Commissioner's Office (ICO), the UK supervisory authority for data protection issues ([ico.org.uk](https://ico.org.uk/)). We would, however, appreciate the chance to deal with your concerns before you approach the ICO so please contact us in the first instance.

_**Changes to the privacy notice and your duty to inform us of changes**_

This version was last updated on 25 May 2018 and historic versions can be obtained by contacting us.

It is important that the personal data we hold about you is accurate and current. Please keep us informed if your personal data changes during your relationship with us.

_**Third-party links**_

Our website may include links to third-party websites, plug-ins and applications. Clicking on those links or enabling those connections may allow third parties to collect or share data about you (e.g. you may decide to create an account on the website by using your Facebook, Twitter or Google log in and this may mean that Facebook and Twitter can better target our promoted posts on Facebook or Twitter). We do not control these third-party websites and are not responsible for their privacy statements. When you leave our website, we encourage you to read the privacy notice of every website you visit.

**2\. The data we collect about you**

Personal data, or personal information, means any information about an individual from which that person can be identified. It does not include data where the identity has been removed (anonymous data).

We may collect, use, store and transfer different kinds of personal data about you which we have grouped together as follows:

  * _**Identity Data**_ includes first name, last name, any previous last name, username or similar identifier, title, date of birth, gender and details about your hobbies and interests, education, volunteering experience and previous and current employment details. 
  * _**Contact Data**_ includes billing address, delivery address, email address and telephone numbers.
  * _**Financial Data**_ includes bank account and payment card details.
  * _**Transaction Data**_ includes details about payments to and from you and other details of products and services you have purchased from us.
  * **_Technical Data_** includes internet protocol (IP) address, your login data, authentication from Facebook, Twitter or Google (if you create an account on the website by using your Facebook, Twitter or Google log in), browser type and version, time zone setting and location, browser plug-in types and versions, operating system and platform and other technology on the devices you use to access our website. 
  * _**Profile Data**_ includes your username and password, purchases or orders made by you, your interests, preferences, feedback and survey responses.  
  * _**Usage Data**_ includes information about how you use our website, products and services. 
  * _**Marketing and Communications Data**_ includes your preferences in receiving marketing from us and our third parties and your communication preferences.

We also collect, use and share _**Aggregated Data**_ such as statistical or demographic data for any purpose. Aggregated Data may be derived from your personal data but is not considered personal data in law as this data does not directly or indirectly reveal your identity. For example, we may aggregate your Usage Data to calculate the percentage of users accessing a specific website feature. However, if we combine or connect Aggregated Data with your personal data so that it can directly or indirectly identify you, we treat the combined data as personal data which will be used in accordance with this privacy notice.

We do not collect any _**Special Categories of Personal Data**_ about you (this includes details about your race or ethnicity, religious or philosophical beliefs, sex life, sexual orientation, political opinions, trade union membership, information about your health and genetic and biometric data). Nor do we collect any information about criminal convictions and offences.

_**If you fail to provide personal data**_

Where we need to collect personal data by law, or under the terms of a contract we have with you and you fail to provide that data when requested, we may not be able to perform the contract we have or are trying to enter into with you (for example, to provide you with goods or services). In this case, we may have to cancel a product or service you have with us but we will notify you if this is the case at the time. 

**3\. How is your personal data collected?**

We use different methods to collect data from and about you including through:

  * **Direct interactions.** You may give us your Identity, Contact and Financial Data by filling in forms or by corresponding with us by post, phone, email or otherwise. This includes personal data you provide when you:
  * apply to write for us;
  * create an account on our website (including when you apply to become a website member or a registered user or create a profile so that you can request listings of your events be added to the website);
  * contact us about one of our services, such as listing your event on the website, or advertising or sponsored content;
  * subscribe to our services or publications;
  * request marketing to be sent to you;
  * enter a competition, promotion or survey;
  * orgive us some feedback.
  * _**Automated technologies or interactions.  **_As you interact with our website, we may automatically collect Technical Data about your equipment, browsing actions and patterns. We collect this personal data by using cookies, server logs and other similar technologies. We may also receive Technical Data about you if you visit other websites employing our cookies. Please see our [cookie policy](https://bachtrack.com/cookie-policy) for further details.
  * _**Third parties or publicly available sources.**_ We may receive personal data about you from various third parties and public sources.
  * _Technical Data_ from the following parties:
  * authentication from Facebook, Twitter or Google if you create an account on the website using your Facebook, Twitter or Google log in;
  * analytics providers; and
  * search information providers.
  * _Contact, Financial and Transaction Data_ from providers of technical, payment and delivery services.
  * _Identity and Contact Data_ from publicly availably sources such as Companies House and the Electoral Register.

**4\. How we use your personal data**

We will only use your personal data when the law allows us to. Most commonly, we will use your personal data in the following circumstances:

Where we need to perform the contract we are about to enter into or have entered into with you.

Where it is necessary for our legitimate interests (or those of a third party) and your interests and fundamental rights do not override those interests.

Where we need to comply with a legal or regulatory obligation.

Generally we do not rely on consent as a legal basis for processing your personal data other than in relation to sending third-party direct marketing communications to you via email or text message. You have the right to withdraw consent to marketing at any time by contacting us or following the instructions to unsubscribe in the email or text message.

_**Purposes for which we may use your personal data**_

We have set out below, in a table format, a description of all the ways we plan to use your personal data, and which of the legal bases we rely on to do so. We have also identified what our legitimate interests are where appropriate.

Note that we may process your personal data for more than one lawful ground depending on the specific purpose for which we are using your data. Please contact us if you need details about the specific legal ground we are relying on to process your personal data where more than one ground has been set out in the table below. 

**Purpose/Activity**

| 

**Type of data**

| 

**Lawful basis for processing including basis of legitimate interest**  
  
---|---|---  
  
To deliver particular website content to you as a registered user of the website (authors are required to become a registered user of the website)

| 

(a) Identity

(b) Contact

(c) Profile

(d) Usage

(e) Technical

(f) Marketing and Communications

| 

(a) Performance of a contract with you

(b) Necessary for our legitimate interests (so that we can identify authors and you can request to write articles and attend events to write articles about such events for our website, to run our business, so that our website and business can continue to grow and develop, so we can tailor our services that we provide you with and how you would like to be contacted)  
  
To contact you as an author in connection with you producing, amending and completing articles for our website and to stay in contact with you as an author

| 

(a) Identity

(b) Contact

(c) Financial (most authors are unpaid volunteers but we may need these details if we have agreed a payment with you)

(d) Transaction

(e) Profile

(f) Marketing and Communications

| 

(a) Performance of a contract with you

(b) Necessary for our legitimate interests (for running our business, to help our website and business to continue to grow and develop, so that we know how you would like to be contacted and what you would like to receive from us)  
  
To provide information about you as an author on the website

| 

(a) Identity

| 

Necessary for our legitimate interests (for providing information to website visitors about the author and other articles written by the author. Note that you write the ‘about the author’ information that you would like us to use).  
  
To obtain tickets from third parties for you as an author so that you can attend and write about events on our behalf

| 

(a) Identity

(b) Contact

| 

Performance of a contract with you  
  
To stay in contact with you as a customer or prospective customer

| 

(a) Identity

(b) Contact

(c) Profile

(d) Usage

(e) Marketing and Communications

| 

(a) Performance of a contract with you

(b) Necessary for our legitimate interests (for running our business, to help our business to grow and develop, to tailor the services we offer to you and so that we know how you would like to be contacted and what you would like to receive from us)  
  
To allow you as a customer/ prospective customer to create and use a website profile to request listings of your events be added to the website or to request advertising or sponsored content be added to the website

| 

(a) Identity

(b) Contact

(c) Financial

(d) Transaction

(e) Technical

(f) Profile

(g) Usage

(h) Marketing and Communications

| 

(a) Performance of a contract with you

(b) Necessary for our legitimate interests (to help our business grow and develop, to tailor the services we offer to you and so that we know how you would like to be contacted and what you would like to receive from us)  
  
To process and deliver your orders or requests for one of our products or services (such as listing your event on the website, or advertising or sponsored content) including:

(a) Manage payments, fees and charges

(b) Collect and recover money owed to us

| 

(a) Identity

(b) Contact

(c) Financial

(d) Transaction

(e) Profile

(f) Usage

(g) Marketing and Communications

| 

(a) Performance of a contract with you

(b) Necessary for our legitimate interests (to help our business grow and develop, to recover debts due to us, to tailor the services we offer to you and so that we know how you would like to be contacted and what you would like to receive from us)  
  
To deliver exclusive website content to you as a website member, including:

(a) Manage payments, fees and charges

(b) Collect and recover money owed to us

| 

(a) Identity

(b) Contact

(c) Financial

(d) Transaction

(e) Technical

(f) Profile

(g) Usage

(h) Marketing and Communications

| 

(a) Performance of a contract with you

(b) Necessary for our legitimate interests (to help our business grow and develop, to recover debts due to us, to study how website members use our website, to tailor the services that we offer to you and so that we know how you would like to be contacted and what you would like to receive from us)  
  
To manage our relationship with you which will include:

(a) Notifying you about changes to our terms or privacy policy

(b) Asking you to leave a review, take a survey or provide other feedback

| 

(a) Identity

(b) Contact

(c) Profile

(d) Marketing and Communications

| 

(a) Performance of a contract with you

(b) Necessary to comply with a legal obligation

(c) Necessary for our legitimate interests (to keep our records updated and to study how users use our website and how users use the products/services we offer)  
  
To enable you to partake in a competition, to complete a survey or to provide other feedback

| 

(a) Identity

(b) Contact

(c) Profile

(d) Usage

(e) Marketing and Communications

| 

(a) Performance of a contract with you

(b) Necessary for our legitimate interests (to study how users use our website and how users use products/services we offer, to develop them and grow our business)  
  
To administer and protect our business and our website (including troubleshooting, data analysis, testing, system maintenance, support, reporting and hosting of data)

| 

(a) Identity

(b) Contact

(c) Technical

| 

(a) Necessary for our legitimate interests (for running our business, provision of administration and IT services, network security, to prevent fraud)

(b) Necessary to comply with a legal obligation  
  
To deliver relevant website content and advertisements to you and measure or understand the effectiveness of the advertising we serve to you

| 

(a) Identity

(b) Contact

(c) Technical

(d) Profile

(e) Usage

(f) Marketing and Communications

| 

Necessary for our legitimate interests (to study how you use our website, products and services, to develop the website, products and services, to grow our business and to inform our marketing strategy)  
  
To use data analytics to improve our website, products and services, marketing and relationships and experiences with you (including registered users, authors, website members, prospective customers and customers)

| 

(a) Technical

(b) Usage

| 

Necessary for our legitimate interests (to define types of prospective customers and customers for our website, products and services, to keep our website updated and relevant, to develop and promote our business and to inform our marketing strategy)  
  
To make suggestions and recommendations to you about products/services that may be of interest to you

| 

(a) Identity

(b) Contact

(c) Technical

(d) Usage

(e) Profile

(f) Marketing and Communications

| 

Necessary for our legitimate interests (to develop our website and any other products/services and grow our business)  
  
_**  
Marketing**_

 We strive to provide you with choices regarding certain personal data uses, particularly around marketing and advertising. 

_**Promotional offers from us**_

We may use your Identity, Contact, Technical, Usage and Profile Data to form a view on what we think you may want or need, or what may be of interest to you. This is how we decide which articles on our website, products, services and offers may be relevant for you (we call this marketing). 

You will receive marketing communications from us if you have requested information from us, or purchased any of our products or services (including requested listings of your events, or advertising or sponsored content) or if you provided us with your details when you entered a competition or registered for a promotion and, in each case, you have not opted out of receiving that marketing.

_**Third-party marketing**_

We will get your express opt-in consent before we share your personal data with any company outside our group of companies for marketing purposes. 

_**Opting out**_

_** **_ You can ask us or third parties to stop sending you marketing messages at any time by contacting us at any time or by following the instructions on the message to unsubscribe.

 Where you opt out of receiving marketing messages, this will not apply to personal data provided to us as a result of a product/service purchase, any warranty registration, product/service experience or other transactions.

_**Cookies**_

You can set your browser to refuse all or some browser cookies, or to alert you when websites set or access cookies. If you disable or refuse cookies, please note that some parts of this website may become inaccessible or not function properly. For more information about the cookies we use, please see our [cookie policy](https://bachtrack.com/cookie-policy).

_**Change of purpose**_  

We will only use your personal data for the purposes for which we collected it, unless we reasonably consider that we need to use it for another reason and that reason is compatible with the original purpose. If you wish to get an explanation as to how the processing for the new purpose is compatible with the original purpose, please [contact us](https://bachtrack.com/contact). 

If we need to use your personal data for an unrelated purpose, we will notify you and we will explain the legal basis which allows us to do so.

Please note that we may process your personal data without your knowledge or consent, in compliance with the above rules, where this is required or permitted by law.

**5\. Disclosures of your personal data**

We may have to share your personal data with the parties set out below for the purposes set out in the table in section 4 above.

  * Internal Third Parties as set out in the Glossary.
  * External Third Parties as set out in the Glossary.
  * Third parties to whom we may choose to sell, transfer, or merge parts of our business or our assets. Alternatively, we may seek to acquire other businesses or merge with them. If a change happens to our business, then the new owners may use your personal data in the same way as set out in this privacy notice. 

We require all third parties to respect the security of your personal data and to treat it in accordance with the law. We do not allow our third-party service providers to use your personal data for their own purposes and only permit them to process your personal data for specified purposes and in accordance with our instructions.

**6\. International transfers**

Some of our external third parties may be based outside the European Economic Area (EEA) so the processing of your personal data may involve a transfer of data outside the EEA

.Whenever we transfer your personal data out of the EEA, we ensure a similar degree of protection is afforded to it by ensuring at least one of the following safeguards is implemented:

We will only transfer your personal data to countries that have been deemed to provide an adequate level of protection for personal data by the European Commission. For further details, see [European Commission: Adequacy of the protection of personal data in non-EU countries](https://ec.europa.eu/info/law/law-topic/data-protection/data-transfers-outside-eu/adequacy-protection-personal-data-non-eu-countries_en).

Where we use certain service providers, we may use specific contracts approved by the European Commission which give personal data the same protection it has in Europe. For further details, see [European Commission: Model contracts for the transfer of personal data to third countries](https://ec.europa.eu/info/law/law-topic/data-protection/data-transfers-outside-eu/model-contracts-transfer-personal-data-third-countries_en).

Where we use providers based in the US, we may transfer data to them if they are part of the Privacy Shield which requires them to provide similar protection to personal data shared between the European Union and the US. For further details, see [European Commission: EU-US Privacy Shield](https://ec.europa.eu/info/law/law-topic/data-protection/data-transfers-outside-eu/eu-us-privacy-shield_en).

Please [contact us](https://bachtrack.com/contact) if you want further information on the specific mechanism used by us when transferring your personal data out of the EEA. 

**7\. Data security**

We have put in place appropriate security measures to prevent your personal data from being accidentally lost, used or accessed in an unauthorised way, altered or disclosed. In addition, we limit access to your personal data to those employees, agents, contractors and other third parties who have a business need to know. They will only process your personal data on our instructions and they are subject to a duty of confidentiality.

We have put in place procedures to deal with any suspected personal data breach and will notify you and any applicable regulator of a breach where we are legally required to do so.

**8\. Data retention**

We will only retain your personal data for as long as necessary to fulfil the purposes we collected it for, including for the purposes of satisfying any legal, accounting, or reporting requirements.

To determine the appropriate retention period for personal data, we consider the amount, nature, and sensitivity of the personal data, the potential risk of harm from unauthorised use or disclosure of your personal data, the purposes for which we process your personal data and whether we can achieve those purposes through other means, and the applicable legal requirements.

By law we have to keep basic information about our customers (including Contact, Identity, Financial and Transaction Data) for at least six years after they cease being customers for tax purposes.

Details of other retention periods for different aspects of your personal data are available in our retention policy which you can request from us by contacting us.

In some circumstances you can ask us to delete your data and in some circumstances we may anonymise your personal data (so that it can no longer be associated with you) for research or statistical purposes in which case we may use this information indefinitely without further notice to you. 

**9\. Your legal rights**

Under certain circumstances, you have rights under data protection laws in relation to your personal data.

Please click on the links below to find out more about these rights:

  * Request access to your personal data.
  * Request correction of your personal data.
  * Request erasure of your personal data.
  * Object to processing of your personal data.
  * Request restriction of processing your personal data.
  * Request transfer of your personal data.
  * Right to withdraw consent.

If you wish to exercise any of the rights set out above, please [contact us](https://bachtrack.com/contact). 

_**No fee usually required**_

You will not have to pay a fee to access your personal data (or to exercise any of the other rights). However, we may charge a reasonable fee if your request is clearly unfounded, repetitive or excessive. Alternatively, we may refuse to comply with your request in these circumstances.

_**What we may need from you**_

We may need to request specific information from you to help us confirm your identity and ensure your right to access your personal data (or to exercise any of your other rights). This is a security measure to ensure that personal data is not disclosed to any person who has no right to receive it. We may also contact you to ask you for further information in relation to your request to speed up our response.

_**Time limit to respond**_

We try to respond to all legitimate requests within one month. Occasionally it may take us longer than a month if your request is particularly complex or you have made a number of requests. In this case, we will notify you and keep you updated.

**10\. Glossary**

_**Lawful basis**_

_**Legitimate Interest**_ means the interest of our business in conducting and managing our business to enable us to give you the best service/product and the best and most secure experience. We make sure we consider and balance any potential impact on you (both positive and negative) and your rights before we process your personal data for our legitimate interests. We do not use your personal data for activities where our interests are overridden by the impact on you (unless we have your consent or are otherwise required or permitted to by law). You can obtain further information about how we assess our legitimate interests against any potential impact on you in respect of specific activities by contacting us.

_**Performance of Contract**_ means processing your data where it is necessary for the performance of a contract to which you are a party or to take steps at your request before entering into such a contract.

_**Comply with a legal or regulatory obligation**_ means processing your personal data where it is necessary for compliance with a legal or regulatory obligation that we are subject to.

_**Third Parties**_

_**Internal Third Parties**_

Other companies in our corporate group who may act as joint controllers or processors and who may be based inside our outside the EU.

_**External Third Parties**_

Service providers who may act as processors based inside or outside the EU and who provide IT, system administration and other services. For example, we use UKFast and Amazon Web Services to store data and act as additional servers and we use payment processors (such as Braintree) to process payments for the purposes identified in the table in section 4.

  * Professional advisers who may act as processors including lawyers, bankers, auditors and insurers based inside or outside the EU who provide consultancy, banking, legal, insurance and accounting services.
  * HM Revenue & Customs, regulators and other authorities who may act as processors based inside or outside the EU who require reporting of processing activities in certain circumstances.
  * Email marketing companies/providers (such as Campaign Monitor) and marketing companies/ providers to create and send out our email marketing and newsletters in accordance with the table in section 4.
  * Ticket providers (see the table in section 4), so that we can obtain tickets for you as an author to attend and write about events on our behalf.

**_Your legal rights_**

You have the right to:

_**Request access**_ to your personal data (commonly known as a "data subject access request"). This enables you to receive a copy of the personal data we hold about you and to check that we are lawfully processing it.

_**Request correction**_ of the personal data that we hold about you. This enables you to have any incomplete or inaccurate data we hold about you corrected, though we may need to verify the accuracy of the new data you provide to us.

**_Request erasure_** of your personal data **.** This enables you to ask us to delete or remove personal data where there is no good reason for us continuing to process it. You also have the right to ask us to delete or remove your personal data where you have successfully exercised your right to object to processing (see below), where we may have processed your information unlawfully or where we are required to erase your personal data to comply with local law. Note, however, that we may not always be able to comply with your request of erasure for specific legal reasons which will be notified to you, if applicable, at the time of your request. 

_**Object to processing**_ of your personal data where we are relying on a legitimate interest (or those of a third party) and there is something about your particular situation which makes you want to object to processing on this ground as you feel it impacts on your fundamental rights and freedoms. You also have the right to object where we are processing your personal data for direct marketing purposes. In some cases, we may demonstrate that we have compelling legitimate grounds to process your information which override your rights and freedoms.

_**Request restriction of processing**_ of your personal data. This enables you to ask us to suspend the processing of your personal data in the following scenarios: (a) if you want us to establish the data's accuracy; (b) where our use of the data is unlawful but you do not want us to erase it; (c) where you need us to hold the data even if we no longer require it as you need it to establish, exercise or defend legal claims; or (d) you have objected to our use of your data but we need to verify whether we have overriding legitimate grounds to use it. 

_**Request the transfer**_ of your personal data to you or to a third party. We will provide to you, or a third party you have chosen, your personal data in a structured, commonly used, machine-readable format. Note that this right only applies to automated information which you initially provided consent for us to use or where we used the information to perform a contract with you.

  _ **Withdraw consent at any time**_ where we are relying on consent to process your personal data. However, this will not affect the lawfulness of any processing carried out before you withdraw your consent. If you withdraw your consent, we may not be able to provide certain products or services to you. We will advise you if this is the case at the time you withdraw your consent.
